hello and welcome to the 24th tutorial
on how to program a g-script 2.
so
i have my server back and i'm not sure
why it came back well it came back a
while ago i just never felt i need to
create any more descriptive tutorials
but now i feel like i
like i should so i'm going to start
making these again
now
i'm not sure why my server
was even gone in the first place and i'm
not sure why it came back but you know
whatever
let's start this tutorial now
as you know level editor does not work
on a mac unless you're using like an
emulator
for windows
and in this tutorial i want to explain
how to edit levels with amac
and does not inc or if you don't want to
use level editor so as you can see this
is level letter i created a level called
testing with a single npc that says
hello
and this is how you would usually upload
levels you would save it
click start remote control
levels
right click anything
then double click the level that's how i
usually do it
and how you would do it if you
have level editor but there's another
way to do it actually
what you have to do
is you have to
go into your folder wherever you can
have your
your your levels and you right click the
file
and do open with
and click notepad
notepad will allow you to see the entire
level in text
and you can edit it however you want
but here's the problem with notepad you
see it all clumped up like this
it's very hard to tell what's happening
by the way all these this entire clump
is actually the tiles of the level and
it's very hard to edit it in an actual
text document
so if you're going to be editing tiles i
recommend you do it on a server and then
download the level
or if you have a level that a level
editor to led on level editor
but anyway
this part is the actual npcs
and as you can see it's not very
easy to see what's happening around here
it's all sort of
clumped up but here's how you can make
it not clumped up or and edit things on
a server
so let's close that
and we'll open our out game rc
it can't be the in-game one and what we
do is we go here to the wrench
and we go to download folder
here
browse a folder i already have one so i
press ok
and this is where my levels are going to
be downloaded when i edit them
or choose to download them now
next we go two levels
and let's find our testing level testing
where is it there here it is what we
have to do is we right click it and we
do edit as text
then we'll see all the text in
a nice little
text document
here is the npc's at the bottom and over
here this big giant
block is the
tiles
it's very hard to edit the tiles like
this and i recommend you use a level
editor or if your server has a online
level letter to use that but here's how
you can edit
the npc's
see mpc is when you want to create an
npc an npc end ends the mpc whatever is
in between here is just like any other
npc would be used
this here is the coordinates of where
the npc is created
with 10 15. so let's create an npc that
does something
npc
we'll make it 15 right next to the other
npc 18
and npc end
we're going to go in here
client side
function
on created
so as soon as it's created it's going to
do whatever in the brackets
then put show image
uh
block.png
comma this.x comma this.y
okay i can end that
and oh a space there i don't know if it
matters but whatever now if we click
apply
and we look online
we'll see that a block has been created
we just created this mpc on the server
and it gets updated automatically you
don't even have to upload the file
and if we check our
uh
our
folder where the file is and we double
click it we'll see that it has also been
updated
this is the mpc we just added
okay
and now if we have a level up level
editor open we just close the old level
and open
open the new one
and we'll see that it has been updated
as such
so anyway that concludes this tutorial
you can now edit levels on a server
and if you don't have a mac this is very
useful because it doesn't means you
don't need a level editor
if you're working totally offline you
just need an online level editor and
to do this
and you're good so anyway
that concludes this tutorial and i'll
see you next time